<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Home on Vedant Puri</title><link>https://vpuri3.github.io/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Vedant Puri</description><generator>Hugo -- 0.155.3</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://vpuri3.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thoughts</title><link>https://vpuri3.github.io/thoughts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpuri3.github.io/thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;div class="section-card" &gt;
&lt;h1 id="my-unsolicited-two-cents"&gt;My unsolicited two cents&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;div class="project-card"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="writing-proofs"&gt;Writing Proofs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Part of writing proofs in mathematics is convincing yourself of the reality of the statement, say P. That given the nature of reality, P is the only way things can go, and no other way is feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A way to convince yourself is to &amp;ldquo;stare at it until you believe it is true.&amp;rdquo; The methods sounds passive but in reality is fairly involved. While staring, I run thought experiments in my head imagining all sorts of test functions, sets, and what not &amp;ndash; and wonder how they interact with with the statement P. Over time the visualizations of P in your head become intricate and you become more comfortable with the idea. The aim is to get an exhaustive idea of the nature of P and be able to say with confidence &amp;ldquo;how could it be anything but P!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Work</title><link>https://vpuri3.github.io/work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://vpuri3.github.io/work/</guid><description>&lt;div class="section-card" &gt;
&lt;h1 id="work-summary"&gt;Work summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This page is an extended curriculum viatte with unnecessary commentary. Check out my single page &lt;a href="https://github.com/vpuri3/vpCV/raw/master/vpCV.pdf"&gt;CV&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re feeling lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="project-card"&gt;
&lt;h2 id="bs--university-of-illinois-urbana-champaign"&gt;BS @ University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign from 2015 to 2019, earning Bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees in &lt;em&gt;Mathematics&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Engineering Mechanics&lt;/em&gt;, and a minor in &lt;em&gt;Computational Science and Engineering&lt;/em&gt;. While at university, I became interested in the numerical treatment of partial differential equations for physical modeling. To that effect, I made an attempt to comprehend the entire knowledge stack of computer simulations: I studied Hamiltonian mechanics to learn how physics is modeled; Sobolev spaces to learn the mathematical treatment of differential operators; and numerical algorithms for converting continuous equationsinto solvable problems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>